Test 4. This is the IELTS listening test.
You will hear a number of different recordings and you will have to answer questions on what you hear.
There will be time for you to read the instructions and questions and you will have a chance to check your work.
All the recordings will be played once only.
The test is in four parts.
At the end of the test you will be given ten minutes to transfer your answers to the answer sheet.
Now turn to part one.
Part one.
You will hear a man phoning to inquire about a cleaning service for his apartment.
First you have some time to look at questions one to five.
Part two.
Now listen carefully and answer questions one to five.
Hello. Easy life cleaning services. Jacinta speaking.
Oh hello. I'm looking for a cleaning service for my apartment. Do you do domestic cleaning?
Sure.
Well it's just a one bedroom flat. Do you have a basic cleaning package?
Yes. For a one bedroom flat we're probably looking at about two hours for a clean.
So we do a thorough clean of all surfaces in each room and polish them where necessary.
Does your apartment have carpets?
No I don't have any but the floor would need cleaning.
Of course. We do that in every room and we do a thorough clean of the kitchen and bathroom.
Okay.
Then we have some additional services which you can request if you want.
So for example we can clean your oven for you every week.
Actually I hardly ever use that but can you do the fridge?
Sure. Would you like that done every week?
Yes definitely. And would ironing clothes be an additional service you can do?
Yes of course.
It wouldn't be much just my shirts for work that week.
That's fine and we could also clean your microwave if you want.
No I wipe that out pretty regularly so there's no need for that.
We also offer additional services that you might want a bit less often say every month.
So for example if the inside of your windows need cleaning we could do that.
Yes that'd be good. I'm on the 15th floor so the outside gets done regularly by specialists
but the inside does get a bit grubby.
And we could arrange for your curtains to get cleaned if necessary.
No they're okay but would you be able to do something about the balcony?
It's quite small and I don't use it much but it could do with a wash every month or so.
Yes we can get the pressure washer onto that.
Before you hear the rest of the conversation you have some time to look at questions 6 to 10.
Now listen and answer questions 6 to 10.
Now if you're interested we do offer some other possibilities to do with general maintenance.
For example if you have a problem with water and you need a plumber in a hurry
we can put you in touch with a reliable one who can come out straight away.
And the same thing if you need an electrician.
Right that's good to know. I've only just moved here so I don't have any of those sorts of contacts.
And I don't know if this is of interest to you but we also offer a special vacuum cleaning system
which can improve the indoor air quality of your home by capturing up to 99% of all the dust in the air.
So if you're troubled by allergies this can make a big difference.
Right in fact I don't have that sort of problem but I'll bear it in mind.
Now can you tell me a bit about your cleaning staff?
Of course. So all our cleaners are very carefully selected.
When they apply to us they have to undergo a security check with the police
to make sure they don't have any sort of criminal background.
And of course they have to provide references as well.
Then if we think they might be suitable for the job we give them training for it.
That lasts for two weeks so it's very thorough and at the end of it they have a test.
If they pass that we take them on but we monitor them very carefully.
We ask all our clients to complete a review of their performance after every visit
and to email it to us so we can pick up any problems straight away and deal with them.
Okay well that all sounds good.
And will I always have the same cleaner?
Yes we do our best to organise it that way and we usually manage it.
Good that's fine.
Right so I'd like to go ahead and...
That is the end of part one.
You now have half a minute to check your answers to part one.
Thank you.